viralize.com 2018-05-29

# Privacy Policy - Viralize

Viralize is committed to protecting the privacy of its Users and to treat their data in accordance with the principles of correctness, lawfulness, transparency and confidentiality. In compliance with the purposes and effects of Legislative Decree no. 196 of June 30, 2003 (“Personal Data Privacy Legislation Decree”) and subsequent amendments and modifications, Viralize hereby provides Users with pertinent information regarding the purposes and treatment of their personal data, of which the same is held whenever the User visits the website viralize.com (“ **Site** “) and registers an account. The terms of this Privacy Policy apply to all Viralize Sites and the proprietary Viralize platform (“ **Platform** “), unless otherwise specified to the User in the registration forms provided by Viralize, or otherwise established in specific written agreements between the User and Viralize.

## Data Controller

Pursuant to Legislative Decree no. 196/2003 (Personal Data Privacy Legislation Decree) and subsequent amendments and modifications, Viralize Srl, (“ **Viralize** “) legally registered in Via Santo Spirito 14, Florence, 50124, VAT No. 06355790483, is entitled to handle personal data collected through the Site.

## Purpose of Data Processing

Viralize will make use of the personal data collected from the User for the following purposes:

  * to provide the activity and / or services requested;
  * for the purpose of profiling and marketing previously consented to by the User of advertising or commercial communications related to any sales, promotions, or market research. For example, when signing up for a Mailing List or Newsletter, the e-mail address of the User will automatically be added to a contact list which may be used to send e-mail messages containing information which may be commercial or promotional in nature, related to the activity and/or services provided by Viralize;
  * with prior User consent, for the purpose of third party communications wherein the categories identified below may utilized for commercial communications relating to any sales promotions which may be communicated via SMS/MMS/VMS and/or e-mail;
  * to contact the User by post or e-mail, for the purpose of confirming and/or modifying the information in the possession of Viralize;
  * for the maintenance and technical assistance necessary to provide the goods and services related to the use of the Platform;
  * to improve the quality of the structure of the Platform, as well as for the purpose of creating new services, features and/or characteristics of the same;

## Location and Time of Data Handling

Data is processed at the registered office of Viralize, save any declaration otherwise specified in this document, for the amount of time necessary to provide the activity and / or services requested by the User, or required for the objectives stated in this document. The User may at any time request an interruption in the handling or the deletion of this data. In case of necessity, data may be handled by the staff of other companies that are responsible for the maintenance of the technological aspects of the the Site and/or Platform.

## Types of Data Handled

Viralize works with certain types of information and/or personal data related to the Users that have come into contact with Viralize, for example, by navigating the Site or during the navigation and/or the process of registering a User  account on the Platform, as well as any instance when Viralize is presented with a request for payment on the part of the User in relation to the services connected to the use of the Platform. Viralize may collect and use the following types of data:

 **Data obtained during the navigation of the Site or Platform by a User:**

during the navigation of the Site, Viralize is made aware of certain information such as IP address, time of Site access, method in which the User accessed the server, size of files transferred in response, a numeric code indicating the server data response (successful, error, etc.), and other parameters related to the operating system and the computer environment of the User. This data is utilized for the exclusive means of receiving anonymous statistical information regarding the use of Viralize, and to monitor the correct function of same, and is removed after use. Data can also be used by competent Authorities to ascertain responsibility in the case of cyber crimes against the Site or third parties;

 **Data obtained from the User during and/or after the registration process:**

Viralize may collect and make use of certain information and/or personal data provided voluntarily by the User during the registration process on the Platform. Said information and/or personal data may be provided by the User by filling out the registration form, in which the User may be required, but not limited to, provide information such as first and last names, date of birth, sex, fiscal code, profession, VAT number, address, e-mail address, telephone number, the address of the website or social media profile in which the User is the owner or holder for the purpose of the services offered or requested through the Platform, bank account number or other pertinent baking information necessary to provide payments to the User. The information provided by the User during and/or after the process of registration will be processed by Viralize in accordance with the provisions of the Personal Data Privacy Legislation Decree for the registration and use of the Platform and Services for the purposes specified below.

## Methods for the Treatment and Security of Data

The treatment of personal data takes place with the aid of computer support, or is automated in strict accordance with the above mentioned purposes, in order to ensure the protection and confidentiality of the User’s information under all circumstances.

Viralize indicates and differentiates instances when the User is obligated to provide personal information or is requested to voluntarily provide information, by including an asterisk ( ***** ) symbol next to the obligatory information fields. The conferral of personal data marked as obligatory ( ***** ) is necessary and indispensable in providing the activities and/or services requested (as referred to under section (i)) and make it possible for Viralize to provide the User maximum efficiency in the delivery of services. The absence by the User of personal data requested by may impede Viralize in providing the activities and/or services requested. The information collected and processed is protected by Viralize using physical and logical methods to minimize the risk of unauthorized access, disclosure, loss, or destruction of the same.

## Third Party Data Sharing

In order to fulfil the requested activities carried out by Viralize, personal data may be shared with:

  * persons, companies, or professionals that provide assistance and consultation to the business owners for accounting, administrative, legal, tax, financial purposes and debt collection in relation to the provision of services;
  * individuals, institutions or authorities to which the communication of your personal data is required by virtue of provisions of law or orders of the authorities;
  * with prior User consent, third parties who provide services related to consumer goods, publishing, communications, finance, insurance, clothing, for the purpose of commercial communications relating to any sales promotions by SMS/MMS/VMS and/or e-mail;
  * third party service providers, postal carriers, hosting providers, computer companies, communication agencies.

## Legal Defence

The User’s personal data may be used in the defence of Viralize in any Court of Law or during legal proceedings leading to eventual legal action against improper use of the Platform or related services by the User.

## Information Not Included in the Privacy Policy

Further information related to the treatment of personal data may be requested at any time from Viralize using the contact information indicated on the Contact Us page of the Site.

## Credit Card Information

Credit card information used for eventual payments is not handled by Viralize, but is handled by a third party service  payment provider.

## Cookies

In order to provide a smoother and more intuitive navigation, the Site and Platform make use of Cookie Technology. Cookies are small text extensions stored by the browser on the User’s device with the intent of speeding up the process of analyzing internet traffic, thus improving the User’s access to the services provided by the Site. Cookies may contain information related to the User, collected and archived by the same User’s browser during navigation, some examples of which include the User’s preferences, tastes, interests, etc. The eventual use of data collected by  the Cookies generated by Viralize is for the means of providing the client the best experience possible on the Site, as well as to identify the User and register their preferences for purposes strictly related to the provision of activities and/or service requested by the user. Third party Cookies may be present on certain pages of the Site, for the intent of tracking the functionality of services provided or to personalize said services based on the tastes and preferences of the User. Viralize will not have access to said Cookies, nor will it have control over them. The User may at any time deactivate and /or block the Cookies present in the browser by deactivating and blocking Cookie use through the browser or directly on the User’s device. Deactivating and/or blocking the transmission of Cookies may result in a reduction in the functionality of certain services or limited access to certain areas of the Site. For further information regarding the use of Cookies, please refer to the Cookie Policy present on the Site.

## Rights of the User

The User may at any time exercise the rights referred to in Article 7 of Legislative Decree no. 196/2003. In particular, the User may:

  * obtain confirmation of the existence of personal data, even if not yet registered, and that said data is made available in an intelligible format;
  * request information on the data source, logic, purpose and manner in which it is processed and the identification of the data controller, the person in charge, or any representative in the State territory and the subjects / categories which may be communicated from said data;
  * obtain the cancellation, anonymous transformation or blocking of data treated in violation of the law and the updating, correction or, if interested, the integration of data;
  * declare that the operations referred to above have been made known, including with regards to their content, to the persons for whom the data was communicated or disseminated, unless this requirement proves impossible or involves the use of means clearly disproportionate to the rights being protected;
  * object, in whole or in part, on legitimate grounds, to their treatment, even if pertinent for the purpose of collection;
  * object, in whole or in part, to the treatment of personal data for the purpose of communicating advertising materials or for direct sales or for the fulfillment of market research or commercial communications.
